Free your mind.
The Matrix Reloaded is a adventure, action,
thriller film directed by Lana Wachowski.
The Resistance builds in numbers as humans are freed from
the Matrix and brought to the city of Zion.
Neo discovers his superpowers, including the ability
to see the code inside the Matrix.
With machine sentinels digging to Zion in 72 hours, Neo, Morpheus and
Trinity must find the Keymaker to ultimately reach the Source.
Neo, played by Keanu Reeves.
Morpheus, played by Laurence Fishburne.
Trinity, played by Carrie-Anne Moss.
Agent Smith, played by Hugo Weaving.
Niobe, played by Jada Pinkett Smith.
The Oracle, played by Gloria Foster.
The Matrix Reloaded is a 2003 American science fiction action
film written and directed by the Wachowskis.
It is the sequel to The Matrix (1999) and the second
installment in the Matrix film series.
The film stars Keanu Reeves, Laurence Fishburne, Carrie-Anne Moss, Hugo Weaving, and Gloria Foster who
reprise their roles from the previous film, with Jada Pinkett Smith joining the cast.
In the film, Neo, Morpheus, and Trinity attempt to reach the Source of the Matrix
to end the war as Zion prepares for an invasion from the machines.
The film premiered on May 7, 2003, in Westwood, Los Angeles,
California, and had its worldwide release by Warner Bros.
Pictures on May 15, 2003, including a screening out of
competition at the 2003 Cannes Film Festival.
The video game Enter the Matrix and The Animatrix, a collection of
short animations, supported and expanded the film's story.
The film received generally positive reviews, though most
critics found it inferior to the first film.
It grossed $741.8 million worldwide, breaking Terminator 2: Judgment Day's record for becoming the
highest-grossing R-rated film of all time, until Deadpool surpassed it in 2016.
In addition to being the highest-grossing film in the franchise, it was the third-highest-grossing
film of 2003, behind The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King and Finding Nemo.
A direct sequel titled The Matrix Revolutions was
released six months later on November 5, 2003.
The film explores themes of dying and death, future,
mission, man vs machine, underground world.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.